cpushareownerservices.com 2015-12-18

# Privacy Policy | Computershare United States

Computershare wants to make your on-line experience satisfying and safe. Our aim is to safeguard the privacy and security of your personal information while providing a personalized service that meets your individual preference and needs. At all times we comply with applicable laws and regulations governing the confidentiality and security of information we receive and maintain on your behalf. We operate websites on behalf of several affiliated companies.

#### What information do we obtain about you and what do we use it for?

Computershare collects personal information through our websites primarily to make it easier for you to use our on-line services. Depending on the services which you are accessing, you may be asked to provide personal information such as your name, address, phone number, social security number, e-mail address, bank account details, proxy voting preferences and information on your current shareholdings. We use Social Security numbers for many purposes, especially to comply with federal and state laws such as tax laws and anti-money-laundering laws. We may use personal information to maintain your account or portfolio, to process any requests and to provide you with the best possible service, all in accordance with applicable laws. We may, for example, use your information to update your details across several holdings in your portfolio.

Although we may share your information with Computershare-affiliated companies and with other service providers as necessary to process a transaction or service your account, such parties are legally bound not to disclose the information in any manner, unless required or permitted by law or other governmental regulations. We will not disclose your personal information to anyone outside these parties or sell to any parties for unsolicited marketing purposes.

If you are located in a country outside the United States, personal information you provide on this site may be transferred to, processed and stored in countries outside your location by Computershare, its affiliates and service providers, all in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### Cookies

In order to improve the quality of our website and services, we may from time to time send you what is known as a "cookie" as permitted by applicable laws and regulations. A cookie is a piece of text that a website transfers to your computer's hard drive. This cookie does not allow Computershare access to your hard drive, but it assists in identifying, for example, whether you have visited our website on a previous occasion. Only the site that posted the cookie can read it.

Please note that the websites to which this site may be linked may also make use of their own cookies to collect information from you. Most browsers will automatically accept a cookie, but it may be possible to set your browser to notify you prior to a cookie being sent at which point you can accept or reject it.

Currently, Computershare does not respond to “Do Not Track” signals from browsers.

If you access an online service maintained by Computershare or one of its subsidiaries (for example, Investor Center, which is maintained by Computershare Inc.) we may use a tool called “Google Analytics” which transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. Google Analytics does not identify individual users or associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. We use the information we get from Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie, disable JavaScript, or use the opt-out service provided by Google.

We may share the information we collect via cookies and Google Analytics with our related entities within the Computershare Group including entities located outside of the United States who assist us in supplying our services including through data storage solutions, back-up services and IT support. These entities are generally located in Canada, New Zealand, the United Kingdom and Australia. We may also disclose it to others if required to do so by law.

#### Third Party Collection of Personal Information

Computershare does not permit third party collection of your personal information on this site. Links to third party websites may be provided on this site for informational or other purposes. Computershare is not responsible for any personal information you may choose to submit to a third party website accessed from this site.

#### Security Precautions to Protect Personal Information

We employ appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect your personal information and to ensure that it is not accessed by unauthorized persons. Information is held on secure servers and is encrypted for transfer wherever this is possible. Computershare uses the same type and level of secure encryption used to transmit credit card details over the Internet when buying merchandise online. Our security procedures may also require you to provide proof of identification before we will release personal information to you. This proof may be in addition to any password required to gain access to our online service. Multiple incorrect attempts or invalidation will result in a lockout from the information. We undergo periodic reviews of our security policies and procedures to ensure that our systems are secure and protected.

We recommend that you never divulge your identification numbers, username, or password to anyone else. You should also never write your password down or store it on your computer and you should make sure you change it regularly. Computershare will never initiate an email to you requesting your personal information. If you have further questions about Identity Theft, you may find the [Federal Trade Commission website](http://www.ftc.gov/) helpful.

#### Accessing and Updating Your Information

You may request a copy of the information, which we hold about you by writing to us at our nearest office. There may be a small charge for this service. We also try to ensure that all information, which we hold for you, is accurate. If you find any inaccuracies we will delete these or correct them promptly. Communication with you may be impeded if the information we hold is inadequate or inaccurate.

This Statement only applies to Computershare websites and does not apply to any websites from which you may have linked to this website or to any website to which you may link from this website.

#### Changes to Privacy Policy

Computershare may change this privacy policy from time to time. Each time you visit the website, please see the “Effective Date” to determine if it has been revised since the last time you entered the site. A “Revised” notation will serve as notice to you that a change has been made.

Revised October 7, 2015
